# Cameron Leach

949.422.4800 | cameron.leach@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

Accomplished manager with over 10 years of software engineering experience and a proven track record of leading smoothly executed projects. I am a people-first leader of multiple engineering teams whose goal is to make teams better by establishing a culture focused on detailed and quality execution in an upbeat and collaborative environment. I show great pride in my craft, and believe that developing engineering talent the right way while establishing a higher standard leads to the best products and results.

### **Experience**

### **Disney Consumer Products and Interactive Media**

Glendale, CA

Senior Manager, Software Engineering

Jan 2017-Present

- Technical lead of the web platform engineering team, responsible for the architecture and development of over 50 systems and tools, including content, data and asset management systems that support numerous web and mobile app experiences across the Disney portfolio
- Oversees multiple functional engineering and product development teams, from reliability
  engineering and devops teams focused on uptime, performance and security, to the platform UX
  team with an emphasis on usability and design
- Led large-scale initiative as the primary technical and project leader to move Disney Interactive's main web platform to Google Cloud, featuring more than 30 major systems that support over 800 guest-facing sites, including Disney's flagship responsive websites disney.com and starwars.com, resulting in multi-million dollar cost savings in system operations year over year
- Lead technical partner to platform solutions team, providing technical guidance and custom-built solutions tailored to the needs of multiple stakeholders and global content production teams
- Collaborates with platform leadership on developing strategy and roadmaps for project teams, involving both full-time and contingent workforce resources, that meet the needs of the organization within budget and on time
- Developed a team-wide knowledge share presentation series as a way to enhance engineering skills and knowledge while building a sense of community through informative presentations in a casual environment

## Manager, Software Engineering

Jan 2014-Dec 2016

- Led product and engineering for backend content management and data platform, which powers Disney's flagship responsive websites disney.com and starwars.com
- Provides architectural and technical guidance on site-serving APIs and producer interface applications built with Ruby on Rails backed by MongoDB
- Managed revision of recommendation engine for Disney video portal that suggests related content through machine learning using Hadoop

#### Staff Software Engineer

Jan 2013-Dec 2013

- · Led front end and search engineering teams responsible for newly relaunched disney.com
- Migrated several legacy disney.com sites and portals onto search platform, including Disney Channel, Disney XD and Walt Disney Company corporate sites
- Launched internationalized front end sites and search platforms in Latin America and Europe, supporting multiple languages in a cohesive and integrated ecosystem

- Architected and built an entirely new search platform for the major relaunch of disney.com using open-source software and frameworks like Apache Solr and Spring
- Optimized primary search algorithm leading to an increase in direct affiliate revenue from search on disney.com over 500% year over year
- Search platform includes multiple scalable indices supporting varied clients through a common API including a producer-facing content management system backend as well as other frontfacing sites like disneybaby.com
- Spearheaded automation through continuous integration with Jenkins and Capistrano for scripted deployments
- Worked on a fast-paced agile Labs team whose purpose was to innovate on experimental features, many of which became the foundation for the new disney.com

## CityGrid Media/Citysearch

West Hollywood, CA

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2008-Apr 2011

- Led team of search engineers in deployment of new search functionality during major site redesign with algorithm improvements leading to increases in conversions and revenue of over \$500k per year
- Architected and scaled multiple clusters of Apache Solr-based indexes containing more than
   18 million unique business listings performing advanced geo-spatial local searches
- Responsible for development and deployment of CityGrid public content APIs serving localized business listing profiles, search, deals and user reviews used by more than 100 partners and developers
- Principal engineer on cross-functional scrum team responsible for building RESTful web applications for submission of user generated content including images, reviews and tweets from Twitter
- Built server-side component of auto complete/predictive text functionality using Apache Lucene with index containing over 3 million search terms localized to specific geographic regions
- Built self-enrollment wizard using Spring Webflow for backend customer system for new potential merchant signups

## **Warner Bros. Advanced Digital Services**

Burbank, CA

Associate Application Engineer

May 2006-Apr 2008

- Led development of online video distribution applications for both client and server utilizing
   Java technologies and Windows DRM to generate cost savings of over \$1 million for studio
- Involved in development of several consumer facing Java applications including main portal,
   CRM application, and content management systems

#### Walt Disney TV Animation/DisneyToon Studios

Burbank, CA

Undergraduate Associate

Jun 2005-Aug 2005

- · Improved software scripts, increasing efficiency of the animation production pipeline
- Provided assistance in production archival, system administration and technology upkeep

## Education

## **University of Southern California**

Los Angeles, CA

**Apache Tomcat** 

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering and Computer Science

December 2005

- · Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- · USC Presidential Scholar
- · USC SCion Scholar

**Skills** 

Java (EE, SE) Ruby on Rails

Ruby Sinatra

Google Cloud Platform MongoDB HTML
Google App Engine SQL JavaScript
Google Container Engine Apache Solr CSS

Lucene

Luce

Docker Mac OS X Kubernetes Maven Unix/Linux

Helm Web Services/APIs

REST Agile Methodologies

Spring Framework Scrum

Hibernate Continuous Integration Kanban